He came from nothing. He conquered everything.
Napoleon is a history, war, romance film directed by Ridley Scott.
An epic that details the checkered rise and fall of French Emperor Napoleon Bonaparte and his relentless
journey to power through the prism of his addictive, volatile relationship with his wife, Josephine.
Napoleon Bonaparte, played by Joaquin Phoenix.
Josephine Bonaparte, played by Vanessa Kirby.
Paul Barras, played by Tahar Rahim.
Duke of Wellington, played by Rupert Everett.
Junot, played by Mark Bonnar.
Talleyrand, played by Paul Rhys.
Napoleon is a 2023 epic historical war film directed and co-produced
by Ridley Scott from a screenplay by David Scarpa.
Based on the life of Napoleon and primarily depicting his rise to power, as well as his relationship with
his wife, Joséphine, it stars Joaquin Phoenix as Napoleon and Vanessa Kirby as Joséphine.
In October 2020, Scott announced Napoleon as his next project.
Following delays and recastings due to the COVID-19 pandemic, filming
began in February 2022 in England, lasting several months.
In addition to writer David Scarpa, frequent Scott collaborators included
cinematographer Dariusz Wolski and editor Claire Simpson.
Napoleon premiered at Salle Pleyel in Paris on November 14, 2023, and was released in the United States and United Kingdom on
November 22 by Columbia Pictures (via Sony Pictures Releasing) before streaming on Apple TV+ on March 1, 2024.
The film grossed $222.4 million worldwide and received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the battle sequences
and performances but criticized its uneven tone, rushed pacing, and lack of historical accuracy.
At the 96th Academy Awards, the film received nominations for Best
Production Design, Best Costume Design, and Best Visual Effects.
The film explores themes of empire, france,
general, biography, napoleon bonaparte.
The tone is emotional.